Vyron Vasileiadis

Software Engineer & Trainer

Personal Info

E-mail

hi@fedonman.com

WWW

https://fedonman.com

LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/fedonman

Skills

Web Development

Game Development

Machine & Deep Learning

Internet of Things

Remote Sensing

Microsoft Azure

Training & Coaching

Problem Solving

Senior Software Engineer specialized in Web Technologies with a keen interest and experience in Microsoft Azure, Internet of Things, Smart Cities, Machine & Deep Learning, Ocean Remote Sensing and Quantum Computing.

Microsoft Certified Trainer adept at planning and implementing onsite and remote training programs. Authoritative and clear communicator with a charismatic style and insightful approach.

Based in Athens, Greece. Open to remote positions or attractive relocation packages.

Work History

2019-01 -Current

Microsoft Certified Trainer

Freelancer, Worldwide

Scheduled and taught various in-class and online Microsoft courses either independently or in cooperation with Microsoft Partners. Currently available courses:

- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals
- Designing and Implementing an Azure Al Solution
- Designing and Implementing a Data Science Solution on Azure
- Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3
- Programming in C#
- Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications

2016-10 -Current

Technical Trainer

PeopleCert, Athens, Greece

- Trainer at Alliance for Digital Employability Coding Bootcamp, a 14-week intensive training course, where previously unemployed candidates with no ICT background are re-skilled and certified by PeopleCert as full-stack developers
- Trained over 1000 hours and more than 300 students
 Python, C#, ASP.NET, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
 Angular, React, as well as generic software skills such
 as algorithms, design patterns, OOP, functional
 programming, testing, scrum
- Collaborated with leadership to assist in lesson plans, instructional materials and written practice tests

2014-09 - Co-Founder & Lead Developer

2017-04	Open.tech, Athens, Greece
	 Co-Founder of open.tech, a collaborative creative
	agency in Greece specialized in innovative
	technologies and the web
	 Lead Developer on a plethora of projects for a
	variety of clients including luxury villas, apartments
	and hotels, top Greek fashion designers, theatrical
	groups and the Greek government
	 Worked closely with clients to establish problem
	specifications and system designs

2013-10 -2014-06

Web & Game Developer

Pegneon, Athens, Greece

 Implemented company's website, API and integrated solutions into business operations

Managed a team of 5 developers and designers

 Designed and developed company's main product, an educational game about safety and hygiene in co-working spaces

2012-05 -2012-10

Web Developer

IT Development Spain, Granada, Spain

- Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in website projects
- Used various technologies to make code repairs and optimize corporate website

Education

2015-10 -2017-10

Master of Science: Space Science, Technologies & Applications

University of Peloponnese & National Observatory of Athens - Greece

- The first and only Higher Education Programme in Greece in the domain of Space
- Thesis: "Advancements in monitoring the Mediterranean Sea with the use of Copernicus data"

2007-10 -2013-03

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science & Technology

University of Peloponnese - Greece

• Thesis: "CoveX: Quantum Circuit Simulator"

Elected as Student's Representative for 4 consecutive years

Certifications

2019-01	Microsoft Certified Trainer
2019-01	Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate: Web Development
2019-06	Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Engineer Associate
2019-06	NVIDIA Deep Learning for Computer Vision
2019-10	Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Scientist Associate

Additional Training

- Copernicus Marine Service for the Aquaculture Sector, Athens, Greece, 24 - 25 September 2019
- ESA Advanced Ocean Remote Sensing Training
 Course at Porto, Portugal, 11 17 September 2017
- Third International Ocean Colour Science Meeting at Lisbon, Portugal, 15-18 May 2017
- Quantum Complex Systems Summer School at University of Vienna, Austria, 22 - 26 September 2014
- Workshop on Quantum Simulations at Universidad del Pais Vasco UPV/EHU, Bilbao, Spain, 22-25 October 2012

Volunteering

- Technical Trainer at Social Hackers Academy, an NGO programming school for refugees & unemployed EU Nationals
- Mentor at a plethora of innovation hackathons co-organized by Crowdpolicy and Greek public sector